Dave Burt

Software Engineer & Team Player

Phone: 04734220521

Australian Citizen

Portfolio: daveburt.au

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with a background in emergency nursing. I changed careers after discovering a passion for software engineering. I previously worked as a senior nurse for the second busiest emergency department in NSW. There I worked in a close-knit team of emergency specialists who delivered high-quality care for members of the public. In this role, I oversaw numerous complex cases and on a daily basis communicated person to person with the public and Emergency Services. As such, communication and working in teams come naturally to me. I have invested in my software engineering transition by studying with General Assembly, fimilarising myself multiple languages and working with other developers on team projects.

SKILLS

Databases Languages HTML/CSS **PostgreSQL**

JavaScript Python

Methodologies

Frameworks/Libraries

OO Programing MVC/MVT Architecture ResponsiveDesign Principles oftesting

User Stories

ERDs

Express.js React Django Node.js

MongoDB

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior student Software Engineer

General Assembly • Jan 2024 - April 2024

- Daily huddles reporting progress to senior instructions, completing team work and pair programming excerises.
- 700 + hours of coding experience, problem solving, refractoring own and fellow devs code.
- · Best practices such as MVC, naming conventions, resusability, testing & error driven development.
- Developed web forms that collect user data for storage in a database (SQL) with form validation.

Senior Registered Nurse

Mediserve Nursing Agency • 2023 – 2024

- · Collaborated with multdiscipinary teams, patient and family members to design and implement patient-centered care.
- Oversaw junior team members training and skill progression.

Senior Registered Nurse

Wollongong Emergency Department • 2019 - 2023

- · Enhanced documentation standards during COVID-19, leading to quicker identification of exposed staff and patients.
- Consistently achieved rank of top 10 out of 120 nurses for monthly clinical assessments.

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Affordable Communite Finder <u>Live Demo View Code</u>

Worked as a team to develop, test and deploy a single-page React web app that looks up property sales in Sydney relative to a a user defined point of interest and sorts according to travel time and interest. Built using JavaScript, React, CSS, MongoDB and Leaflet.

APIs accessed: OpenStreetMap, TravelTime, Google Places.

Dose Master

<u>Live Demo</u> <u>View Code</u>

Single-page React app that generates realistic medication calculation questions for student nurses to practice with. Developed with consultation from UI/UX designer and nursing students for UI and functionality improvements and testing. Extensifve prompt engineering testing to OpenAi API.

Inclusive Dine

Live Demo View Code

Resturant reviews centered for wheelchair accessibility. Contains a CRUD systems using Node.js and Express.js. Implemented Google OAuth for authenticaton-required functionality MongoDB, Custom CSS. Deployed frontend and backend with Heroku.

Blackheath Wind Meter

View Code

Working in a team with senior developers to record wind speed and direction at Blackheath NSW paraglider take off and display said data on a web app. Built with Arduino, C++, JavaScript, HTML, AWS. I've been streamlining CI/CD using GitHub Actions and currently converting to from JavaScript to TypeScript.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive

General Assembly Australia • Jan 2024 - Apr 2024

Grad Certificate in Emergency Nursing

University of Tasmania • 2019-2020

Advanced Life Support

Australian College of Nursing 2017-2018

Bachelor of Nursing

University of Wollongong 2012-2015